LESLEY CHANG

LINKEDIN GITHUB TWITCH (470) 266-7770 LESLEY.HANNA98@GMAIL.COM

EDUCATION

University of California — B.A. Data Science, Domain Emphasis in Psychology, 2020

Extracurriculars

VP, Pledge Advisor, & Head of Career Fairs for Beta Alpha Psi

Notable Courses

Algorithms (CS 170), Artificial Intelligence (CS 188), Machine Learning (CS 189), Time Series (Stat 153), Stochastic Processes (STAT 150), Probability & Risk Analysis for Engineers (IEOR 172)

SKILLS

Languages

Typescript, Rust, Python, C, Go

Frameworks

React, Next.js, Node, Anchor (Solana)

Other

Product Validation,
Design & Iteration;
Customer Discovery
Research

HOBBIES

Streaming Apex Legends, Digital Art, Guitar

PROFILE

I have 3 years of experience as a Software Engineer at corporations like Apple and startups of various sizes and 1.5 years as a Product Engineer (mix of Product Management and Engineering) at early stage startups, and I am interested in Software Engineer or Product Management roles.

EXPERIENCE

Product Engineer @ Ampersand

February 2021 - Present // Austin, TX

- Became responsible for core engineering workflow across different products and participated in critical product decisions as the company's first hire
- Extracted and maintained reusable components across backend & frontend codebases and boilerplates for bootstrapping new projects with common tooling like ESLint, Prettier, Husky, etc
- Implemented features end-to-end using Rust and Node for backend and Typescript/React/Next for frontend

Collective Lead @ koodos

October 2020 - February 2020 // Boston, MA

- Helped lead a fellowship of young engineers and designers for building product experiments around creative expression
- Taught about ideating and designing viable product experiments, conducting customer discovery research and user interviews, as well as product iteration
- Mentored and helped engineers with technical decisions, especially for building in bootstrapped and fast-paced environments

Founding Engineer @ Seren

October 2020 - February 2020 // Berkeley, CA

- Lead the development for a platform focused on solving the problems related to remote team productivity and retention
- Participated in National Science Foundation's Innovation Corps program's June 2021 Cohort, a bootcamp focused on customer discovery research, product ideation, validation, and iteration

Software Engineer Intern, Cloud Data @ Apple

May 2019 - August 2019 // Curpertino, CA

- Developed prototypes of a tool for Apple's data center teams to act as the source of truth and inventory for data center assets, totalling \$100M
- Worked with various organizations within Apple to extract data from an existing API, transform the data to fit my use case, and publish it to the Kafka topic